让我们总结一下我们在本次讲座中学到的一些主要观点。有
Let’s summarize some of the main ideas that we have learned in this lecture. There is
路径和轨迹之间的重要区别。路径是空间构造
an important distinction between a path and a trajectory. A path is a spatial construct
并告诉我们如何通过世界从A到B。轨迹是路径加上时间表。
and tells us how we get from A to B through the world. A trajectory is a path plus a schedule.
它告诉我们我们应该多快地沿着这条路走，我们应该在什么时候做什么
It tells us how quickly we should move along the path, at what time we should be at what
沿着路径指向。轨迹与位置和方向一样重要
point along the path. It’s important with trajectories that the position and orientation
与时间顺利变化。我们这样做有很多原因。我们希望减少最大值
vary smoothly with time. We do this for a number of reasons. We want to reduce the maximum
机器人加速，允许我们减小电机的尺寸，它可能会减少
acceleration on the robot, allows us to reduce the size of the motors, and it perhaps reduces
在机器人结构中引起的振动。平滑的意思是什么意思
vibrations induced in the structure of the robot. What the smooth mean would mean that
作为时间的函数，位置是连续的，并且速度是连续的函数
the position is continuous as a function of time and velocity is continuous as a function
时间而且，我们希望加速是连续的，也许是混蛋是连续的
of time. And, we would hope that the acceleration is continuous and perhaps the jerk is continuous
等等通过高阶导数。在机器人技术中，一种常见的生成技术
and so on up through higher-order derivatives. In robotics, a common technique for generating
轨迹是使用多项式，通常是具有六个系数的五次多项式
a trajectory is to use a polynomial, typically, a quintic polynomial which has got six coefficients
这让我们可以独立指定六个边界条件，即初始和最终位置，
which lets us independently specify six boundary conditions, the initial and final position,
初始和最终速度，初始和最终加速度。而且，我们可以写这么简单
initial and final velocity, initial and final acceleration. And, we can write this simple
矩阵关系给出了系数值作为轨迹时间的函数，
matrix relationship which gives us the coefficient values as a function of the trajectory time,
资本T和边界条件。然而，多项式存在性能问题
capital T, and the boundary conditions. There is, however, a performance problem with polynomial
轨迹，即峰值速度几乎是平均速度的两倍，我们就是这样
trajectories and that is that the peak velocity is almost twice the average velocity and we’re
浪费电机性能，有效地花费两倍的时间来到达我们想要的地方
wasting motor performance and effectively taking twice as long to get where we want
到达，得到。所谓的更有效的轨迹
to get to. A more efficient trajectory is what’s called
梯形轮廓，我们有一些加速阶段，然后是滑行
the trapezoidal profile where we have some acceleration phase followed by a coasting
或恒速阶段，然后是减速阶段。有点不利
or constant velocity phase, followed by a deceleration phase. A slight disadvantage
梯形曲线的二阶导数，加速度是不连续的，
of the trapezoidal profile is that the second derivative, the acceleration is discontinuous,
但它有很多很多其他的优点，非常常用于机器人和机器
but it has many, many other virtues and very, very commonly used in robotics and machine
工具控制。如果我们想通过一些中间点从一个点移动到另一个点
tool control. If we want to move from one point to another through a few intermediate
我们通过点或路点呼叫的点，然后为了实现连续性
points which we call via points or way points, then in order to achieve continuity in the
路径，我们需要介绍所谓的混合，它们在这里以红色显示。我们
path, we need to introduce what are called blends and they are shown here in red. We
引入一个加速周期，从速度前进到例如，
introduce an acceleration period to transition from the velocity heading towards, for instance,
第2点指向我们需要朝向第3点的速度。缺点是我们
point 2 in to the velocity we need to head towards point 3. The disadvantage being we
从来没有真正达到我们前进的目的。
never actually get to the point that we’re heading for.
如果加速时间很短，我们会非常接近通孔点，但加速度
If the acceleration time is small, we get very close to the via points, but the acceleration
在机器上很高。加速时间很长，然后是机器人的加速度
on the machine is high. Acceleration time is large, then the acceleration of the robot
很低，但我们错过了更多的通过点。我们介绍了插值的概念
is low, but we miss the via points by a larger amount. We introduced the notion of interpolating
在基于标量S的初始值和最终值之间，其在0之间变化
between an initial value and a final value based on a scalar S which varies between 0
和0给出了初始值，1给出了最终值，0.5是中间值
and 1. 0 gives us the initial value, 1 gives us the final value, and 0.5 is halfway in
之间。X可以是矢量。并且，如果S是时间的平滑函数，那么X也是如此。
between. X can be a vector. And, if S is a smooth function of time, then so is X.
我们讨论了如何不将这种简单的插值方案应用于旋转矩阵。
We talked about how we cannot apply this simple interpolation scheme to rotation matrices.
旋转矩阵是特殊的。它们是正交矩阵。所以，将其中两个加在一起
Rotation matrices are special. They are orthogonal matrices. So, adding two of them together
不会导致另一个正交矩阵。所以，我们不对旋转矩阵这样做。
does not result in another orthogonal matrix. So, we don’t do this to rotation matrices.
相反，我们可以做的是将旋转转换为一组角度。它可能是欧拉角，
Instead, what we can do is convert our rotation to a set of angles. It could be Euler angles,
它可以是滚动，俯仰，偏航角度，我们可以插入它们。我们介绍了方向
it could be roll, pitch, yaw angles, and we can interpolate those. We introduced the direction
问题。当我们插入从初始值到最终值的角度时，它就是
problem. When we’re interpolating an angle from an initial value to a final value, it’s
重要的是要记住，我们可以通过两种方式绕圈子旅行。我们可以旅行
important to remember that there are two ways we can travel around the circle. We can travel
这里用蓝色显示的长路，或用红色显示的短路
the long way which is shown here in blue, or the short way which is shown here in red
通过Theta的值等于pi。我们可以插入四元数。我们需要一个更复杂的
through the value of Theta equals pi. We can interpolate quaternions. We need a more complex
这样做的公式。再次插值是S和S的函数变化
formula in which to do this. Interpolation, once again, is a function of S and S varies
从0到1.并且，该插值中的一个重要参数是确定的Theta
from 0 to 1. And, an important parameter in this interpolation is Theta which is determined
从初始和最终四元数的参数。四元数插值提供
from the parameters of the initial and final quaternion. Quaternion interpolation provides
两个方向之间最短和最直接的路径。
the shortest and most direct path between two orientations.
该图显示了正在经历不同的矢量尖端的位置
This figure shows the position of the tip of a vector which is undergoing different
旋转插补的类型。白色路径是由四元数插值引起的，
types of rotational interpolation. The white path is due to quaternion interpolation and,
如上所述，它是最短，最直接的路径。我们可以看到欧拉
as just mentioned, it’s the shortest and most direct path. We can see that the Euler
角度和滚动，俯仰，偏航角插补路径偏离。这意味着他们
angle and roll, pitch, yaw angle interpolation paths deviate from that. That means that they
在两个方向之间采取更长，更间接的路径。最后，我们来了
take a longer and more indirect path between the two orientations. Finally, we come to
姿势插值，通常称为笛卡尔插值。我们有两个姿势，姿势0和
pose interpolation, often referred to as Cartesian interpolation. We have two poses, pose 0 and
姿势1，每个由旋转矩阵和平移向量表示。我们可以转换
pose 1, which each represented by a rotation matrix and a translation vector. We can convert
旋转矩阵到四元数。插值翻译非常简单。我们应用线性
the rotation matrix to a quaternion. Interpolating the translation is very simple. We apply linear
插值到平移分量，然后我们应用四元数插值
interpolation to the translational component, and then we apply quaternion interpolation
到旋转组件。我们可以将插值的四元数转换回旋转
to the rotation component. We can convert the interpolated quaternion back to a rotation
矩阵，将其与插值翻译相结合
matrix, combine it with the interpolated translation
如果这就是我们想要的，那就重建一个同质的转变。
to rebuild a homogeneous transformation if that’s what we want.